46568 Whitechapel Way, Sterling, VA 20165 www.michaelchladon.com

703-597-1694

Summary

Senior Computer Science Major with a passion for developing innovative technical solutions and delivering quality products. Successfully completed several personal and academic projects, learned new skills quickly in time-sensitive environments, and gained valuable industry experience through an internship at a major technology consulting firm.

Education

James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA, Computer Science Major, Computer Information Systems Minor

- Graduating May 2021, Current GPA: 3.8
- Second Century STEM Scholarship Four Year Recipient

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, C, Python, SQL, Solidity
- Web Development: Node.js, Express, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Databases and Data Visualization: mySQL, MongoDB, Microsoft Access, Tableau, MongoDB Charts, Mapbox
- Development Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Git, VirtualBox, Ganache
- Agile Methodology with Scrum

Work Experience

Booz Allen Hamilton, McLean, VA

Digital Solutions Intern June 2019 - August 2019

Developed a blockchain-supported dashboard for exchanging and tracking custom-built utility tokens

- Developed a web application using Node.js, Python and Tableau data visualization tools
- Developed, tested and deployed smart contracts written in Solidity to a local blockchain on Ganache
- Developed the product from start to finish using Scrum
- Created an efficient and informative project presentation and presented it to senior leadership

Digital Solutions Intern Summer 2020

• Accepted a returning internship offer for Summer 2020. Program cancelled due to COVID-19

In The Pits Media, Chantilly, VA

December 2014 - March 2019

Radio Show Engineer and Social Media Coordinator

Gained valuable experience in finding technical solutions in a time-sensitive environment

- Successful production of the weekly radio show, In The Pits Racing Radio, running audio and video components
- Maintained the company website and social media accounts with content, Facebook page reach increased by 35%
- · Secured and conducted exclusive interviews with Formula 1, NASCAR and IndyCar drivers

Technical Achievements

songtrace Web Application - Personal Project

Summer 2020

Independently conceived and developed a web application designed to document and visualize memories associated with songs

- Built a multi-user web app with Node.js, Express, MongoDB back-end and HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap front-end
- Integrated APIs (Spotify, MapQuest) and data visualization libraries (Mapbox, MongoDB Charts)
- Deployed application using Heroku (songtrace.herokuapp.com) and MongoDB Atlas

Optimizing Pathfinding Algorithms Using Parallel and Distributed Computing - Course Project

January 2020 - May 2020

Semester-long research project in a small group with the goal of analyzing the effects of parallelizing four existing algorithms

- As project leader and developer, defined the research topic, set goals and strategies and implemented algorithms
- Wrote a detailed report describing the experimental process and findings

yourFlix Entertainment Database - Course Project

January 2019 - May 2019

Developed an entertainment database using mySQL and existing IMDb data

- Normalized a dataset containing millions of entries to integrate into database
- Created E/R diagrams to develop database schema and wrote SQL scripts to create database tables and insert data
- Assisted with creation of web front-end to allow users to query the database

PiCam - Personal Project Summer 2018